JEM WALKER

Graduate student in translation and interpretation between English and French

+1-720-548-0171 • jem@jemwalker.co

Translation and interpretation student at the Middlebury Institute. Exploring possible specializations but eager for experience in a wide range of domains. Passionate about bridging divides between people. Outside of languages, experience in the political field. Developed negotiation skills working with stakeholders and constituents.

LANGUAGES

A: English

(UK and US variants)

B: French

C: Spanish

SKILLS

- Translation
- Interpretation (consecutive and simultaneous)
- MT post-editing
- Proofreading
- Research and source analysis
- Desktop publishing
- Software
 - » CAT tools (Trados, MemoQ, WordFast Pro)
 - » Microsoft Office Suite
 - » Adobe Creative Cloud
 - » Front-end web design (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery)

AWARDS

1st Prize, 15th United Nations St. Jerome Translation Contest (Student), 2020

EXPERIENCE

Asiatis Translation Agency Intern

Montréal, Québec

Jun-Sep 2020

• Translate and proofread various academic and technical texts as well as participating in video game localization projects

Office of the Governor of Colorado Intern

Denver, Colorado Sep-Nov 2018

- Helped communicate the Governor's vision by writing copy for the Governor's proclamations and correspondence with constituents
- Completed other creative and administrative tasks as required

Administrative Assistant / Citizens' Advocate Nov 2018 – Jan 2019

- Continued responsibilities and projects from internship
- Frontline role, engaging with constituents and providing operational support

Scheduling Assistant

Jan-Jun 2019

- Joined scheduling team in new administration
- Established processes to ensure that the Governor's time was optimally
- Connected with stakeholders to keep the day-to-day business of government running smoothly

Académie de Clermont-Ferrand Enalish Assistant/Teacher

Auvergne, France Oct 2016-Apr 2017

- Developed English-language conversation skills in students aged 11-21
- Responded dynamically to different students' levels of aptitude to help each student achieve maximum progress

Elk Meadow Partners Recruitment Administrative Assistant and Webmaster

Evergreen, Colorado Aug-Sep 2015

- Data input and industry research
- Designed and coded a new website for the firm from scratch in order to extend its reach

EDUCATION

Middlebury Institute of International Studies Monterey, California

MA Translation and Interpretation (FR-EN) 2019-present

University of Leeds

Leeds, England

2015

BA French and Politics (2:1 classification) 2014-2018

Korea University

Seoul, South Korea

International Summer Campus

American Foreign Policy and Korean Language

THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONSIDERATION

+1-720-548-0171 • jem@jemwalker.co